

Pran Kishore

Mobile App Developer (iOS)

Kolkata, West Bengal, India

## **Profile**

I am a native mobile application developer with 7+ years of experience in iOS. I believe design and code both play an important role in the success of an app. My passion is to analyze the app requirements, take it through the entire life cycle from design to production.

# Experience

Tech Lead (iOS) - Optimize IT Systems Pvt. Ltd. Mar 2019 - Present

Leading a team of iOS developers and set up development best practices, Estimating time and effort for projects. Providing training & knowledge sharing sessions.

Associate Consultant - Atos India Pvt. Ltd.

May 2015 - March 2019

Analysing client requirements, suggesting feasible mobile solutions, Estimating time and effort for projects, assisting teams across the globe, for developing mobile practice. Providing training & knowledge sharing sessions.

Software Engineer - Customer First InfonetPvt. Ltd Jan 2014 - May 2015

Developing iOS Mobile Application, working in a dedicated hiring model for offshore clients. Sharing code via GIT / SVN, Writing unit test code, distributing build's to internal testers as well as clients via various platforms. Evaluating app store guidelines & project readiness for uploading to the app to store.

Software Engineer – Micronix Technologies Pvt.Ltd. June 2013 – Jan 2014

Evaluating client requirement, planning UI & UX with the design team, coding the recommended application, Monetizing the app with Ad's, publishing the app on the store.

## **Passion**

Writing code for iOS

Case Study & Estimation

Testing (Automated & Manual)

Exploring different platforms

## **Tools Used**

Xcode 10

**Eclipse** 

Sql Developer

Sketch

# Languages Known

English

Hindi

Bengali

### **Details**

11/10, (882), Purbalaya Purbachal Main Road Near pally Unnayan Club Kolkata -700078, India

kishorepran@gmail.com +91-9330568475

Skype: prankishore19

### Core iOS Skills

### Objective C / Swift

Design patterns MVC, Delegation, Singleton.Concurrency management, collection types. ARC, Optional Chaining, Protocols, Extensions, Generics.

#### Frameworks

Address book, Assets Library, Core Graphics / Image /Location / Text/ Video /Motion, Foundation, Health Kit, Map Kit, Media player, Sql Lite 3.0, Security, Social. XCTest for unit & UI testing.

#### **Features**

App extensions, Handoff, UIKit Dynamics, Background fetch ,Siri kit, Size classes, Ineractive APNS, Local notifications , Custom Gesture recognizers,

### **Core Services**

GCD, In app purchase, SQL Lite, Core data.

## App Management

Generating Certificate & provisioning, iTunes connect configuration App store upload, test flight distribution both internal & external, App analytics.

### Xcode / Others

Integration of third party frameworks via COCOA PODS, Instruments, Time profiling, allocation, memory leaks,LLDB, Custom breakpoints, View Debugger, Touch ID, Source editor extensions, Barometer,Three Axis Gyro, Accelerometer. Ethical Hacking - Jailbreaking iPhone, MTM (Man in the Middile attack), Reverse Engineering Binary.

### Education

B.Tech CSE- West Bengal University of Technology 2008-2012 - DGPA - 7.28

Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata, West Bengal

10 +2 Sc. CBSE 2004-2006 - 63%

ST. Josephs Public School, Samastipur, Bihar

10 th ICSE 2003 - 75%

ST. Paul's High School, Patna, Bihar

### IT Skills

Language

Swift 4.1

Objective C

C & C ++

J2E

FITML5, PL/SQL

Database

SQL SERVER2008 ORACLE DATABASE 11g

Server

**APACHE TOMCAT6** 

### Other Skills

High learning curve, Complex Problem solving

Experience in version controlsystems like GIT & SVN, with tools(Source tree) &CMD

Working in a high performing scrum team at Deutsche Bank, Germany delivering app update every 2-3 months.

Passion for taking dev ops role to facilitate team memebers achieving high productivity. Implemented on board Git lab instance on ubuntu 14.04, connected with CI/CD

### Extra activities

Teaching Mathematics to students of class 11th& 12th

Took part in swimming competition in non professional swimmers category at ILSS Kolkata

# **Projects Done**

#### Deutsche Bank Mobile

The new app German Bank Mobile Banking offers the most modern - combined with a simple and intuitive navigation. Take advantage of the most important banking functions now in an entirely new way.

URL: https://itunes.apple.com/de/app/deutsche-bank-mobile/id1040475847?mt=8

Seller - German Bank AG

#### Hear and See

It is an application that allows viewing and listening to the live broadcast TV channels and radio under Saudi Broadcasting Corporation via HTTP Live streaming. Users also have the option to login to the app, comment, rate and social sharing via Twitter, Facebook, Google plus.

URL:- https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/asm-wshahd/id1001907602?mt=8 Seller - Saudi Broadcasting Corporation (SBC)

#### **CGFirst**

This corporate governance app where client's of CGFirst will be able to download the app and will digitize the whole process. Features: Both client and CGfirst personnel may schedule meetings, people will be able to see meeting details and set their RSVP status. All documents in different formats (word, PDF, jpg) will be saved to the cloud for sharing. PDF's handled via world's leading PDF kit – PSPDF will all features such as editing annotations etc.

URL :- https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/cgfirst-ipad-edition/id656360855?mt=8 Seller - Fast Fwd Multimedia Ltd.

## FastAnalytics

Implementation of Google analytics. A user will be able to login to app via Google Auth API confirming access to analytics data with the help of core reporting API's. the main objective was to create a data view that is required by most of the users minus the extra data that is not required in general.

URL :- https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/fast-analytics/id467379850?ls=1&mt=8 Seller - Fast Fwd Multimedia Ltd.

## IndiaMoneyMart - P2P Lending

IndiaMoneyMart (IMM) is a P2P lending and borrowing platform where its registered lenders offer affordable unsecured loan to its registered borrowers/loan applicants.

URL: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/indiamoneymart-p2p-lending/id1347109712 Seller - Fair Vinimay Services Pvt Ltd.

### Leica confocal microscopy (Leica Microsystems)

This application is to promote & advertise the company's products and research facilities. All product launch news & research advancements are posted from the admin panel and is reflected in the app via posts and are arranged in the order of their release date.

URL :- https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/leica-confocal-microscopy/id896704331?mt=8 Seller - Fast Fwd Multimedia Ltd.

### **Awards**

Customer First InfonetPvt. Ltd

Received 'Made a Difference' award for achieving highest customer satisfaction for working in a dedicated hiring model for offshore client and managing overall app lifecycle, from planning to production.

Atos India Pvt. Ltd

Received 'Atos Expert' award for boosting innovation in the company, further improve R&D, setting up highest standards in project delivery to end customer playing key roles from planning to production.

### References

Dr. Subhashis Majumder, Head of Department, Computer Science and Engineering

Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata. Chowbaga Road, Anandapur,

Kolkata 700 107

Email: subhashis.majumder@heritageit.edu

Phone no 9830044136

Debanjan Majumdar - Project Lead

Indus Net Technologies, Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: debanjan.majumdar@gmail.com

Phone no 9748491834

Swarnali Nandy - Project Manager

Indus Net Technologies, Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: swarnali.nandi@indusnet.co.in

Phone no 9830170921

Chiranjib Banerjee - Mobility Consultant

Atos India Pvt. Ltd., Salt lake, Sector V, Kolkata 700 091

Email: chiranjib.banerjee@atos.net

Phone no 9433258064



https://github.com/kishorepran; https://kishorepran.github.io/



https://twitter.com/pran\_kishore; https://medium.com/@kishorepran



https://in.linkedin.com/in/pran-kishore-031795bb



https://www.facebook.com/pran.kishore.1